

### Francisco Pablo Flores Taipe

**Nationality:** Ecuadorian (+49) 17624861016 **Date of birth:** 27/05/1987

**Gender:** Male **Email address:** franciscopabloflores@gmail.com

**Website:** https://www.uni-kassel.de/forschung/en/27/incher/people/flores-francisco

**Website:** <a href="https://www.poverty-action.org/people/francisco-flores">https://www.poverty-action.org/people/francisco-flores</a>

**▼ Twitter:** <a href="https://twitter.com/FrancoPF">https://twitter.com/FrancoPF</a>

• Address: Mönchebergstraße 17, Kassel, 34109 Kassel (Germany)

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a Doctoral student at the University of Kassel (Germany). My research interests are development, inequality, education, behavioral, and gender economics.

I received my MSc. in Economic Behavior and Governance from the University of Kassel in 2018. Between 2018 and 2019, I was also a research fellow at the International Center for Higher Education Research (INCHER).

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### **Doctoral candidate in Economics**

[ 14/05/2018 – Current ]

#### **Master of Science in Economic Behavior and Governance**

**University of Kassel** [ 04/2016 – 04/2018 ]

Address: Kassel (Germany)

Thesis: Showing Life Opportunities: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through

online courses in schools. (Supervisor: Dr. Igor Asanov)

#### **Bachelor of Science in Economics**

**Pontificia Universidad Católica del Ecuador (PUCE)** [ 10/2005 – 12/2011 ]

Address: Quito (Ecuador)

Thesis: El sector eléctrico ecuatoriano en los últimos 20 años : estrategias para alcanzar la seguridad energética

(Supervisor: MSc. Rubén Flores)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Researcher and lecturer at the Faculty of Economics (FB-07)

University of Kassel [ 14/05/2018 - Current ]

City: Kassel

Country: Germany

Research fields: economics of education, development economics, gender economics, behavioral economics, experimental economics.

Teach courses on:

- Behavioral Economics of Poverty
- Economics of Entrepreneurship
- o (Quasi-) Experiments in Entrepreneurship Research
- Field Experiments (Tutorial)
- Intellectual Property Rights (Tutorial)

### Research Assistant at the Economi Policy, Entrepreneurships and Innovation Unit (EPIE) *University of Kassel* [ 02/2017 – 04/2018 ]

City: Kassel

Country: Germany

- Research fields: record linkages, economics of innovation
- Key tasks: literature review, data cleaning, compilation, and preparation.

# Senior consultant at the Quantitative Research Center for Economic and Social Development *Quantitative Research Center for Economic and Social Development (Economica-CIC)* [ 04/2014 – 09/2015 ]

City: Quito

Country: Ecuador

Research fields: health economics, economics of education, gender economics, environmental economics Key tasks:

- Literature review, data analysis, and drafting of policy notes for decision-makers in Ecuador (i.e., the Ministry of Education, National Secretary of Planning)
- Evaluation of multi-media educative solutions to improve students' situation at scale (qualitative and quantitative assessment).
- Dissemination of research results among policymakers and the general audience.
- Capacity-building in team activities.

#### **Economic Coordinator at Ekos Magazine**

**Corporación Ekos** [ 03/2010 – 11/2013 ]

City: Quito

Country: Ecuador

Key tasks:

- Literature review, data analysis, and drafting of journalistic articles about the performance in multiple economic sectors.
- Establishing networks to supply relevant information to our readers.
- Leading teams to audit specialized rankings. The magazine uses the rankings to award the best private companies every year.
- Dissemination of critical information through traditional and non-traditional (digital) media.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

### Remote-learning, time-use, and mental health of Ecuadorian high-school students during the COVID-19 quarantine

[2021]

https://doi.org/10.1016/j.worlddev.2020.105225.

Asanov, Igor, Francisco Flores, David McKenzie, Mona Mensmann, and Mathis Schulte. "Remote-learning, time-use, and mental health of Ecuadorian high-school students during the COVID-19 quarantine." *World development* 138 (2021): 105225.

### Can a role model intervention mitigate the harmful effects of poverty on aspirations? Lessons from Ecuador

[2022]

Francisco Flores. "Can a role model intervention mitigate the harmful effects of poverty on aspirations? Lessons from Ecuador". Working Paper.

### Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[2022]

Asanov, Igor, Atstebro, Thomas; Buenstorf, Guido; Creponm Brunó, Francisco Flores, David McKenzie, Mona Mensmann, and Mathis Schulte. "Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students" Working Paper.

### System-, Teacher-, and Student-level Interventions for Improving Participation in Online Learning at Scale in High Schools

[2022]

Asanov, Igor, Asanov (Noha), Anastasyia, Atstebro, Thomas; Buenstorf, Guido; Creponm Brunó, Francisco Flores, David McKenzie, Mona Mensmann, and Mathis Schulte. "System-, Teacher-, and Student-level Interventions for Improving Participation in Online Learning at Scale in High Schools." Working Paper.

## Empresas y microempresas: identificación de necesidades y demanda de productos, servicios y perfiles laborales deseados en las ciudades de Quito, Guayaquil, y Cuenca

[2015]

Económimca-CIC (2015). Policy brief for the Alto Comisionado para las Naciones Unidas para los Refugiados (ACNUR)

#### **HONOURS AND AWARDS**

#### **Grant secured: SIEF's COVID-19 Emergency Window**

The World Bank Group [ 06/2020 ]

Project: Transitioning from In-School to At-Home Virtual Learning in High Schools: Lessons from Ecuador during the Covid-19 shutdown

https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/sief-trust-fund/brief/covid-19-emergency-window

#### Path to Scale Award

Innovation for Poverty Action (IPA) [ 11/2019 ]

Project: Showing Life Opportunities: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools

https://www.poverty-action.org/program-area/small-and-medium-enterprises/path-to-scale-research

#### **Grant secured: SIEF Nimble evaluations**

The World Bank Group [ 10/2018 ]

Project: Showing Life Opportunities: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools

https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/sief-trust-fund/brief/nimble-summaries

#### **Grant secured: IGL Grants Program**

Innovation Growth Lab (IGL) [ 03/2018 ]

Project: Showing Life Opportunities: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools

https://www.innovationgrowthlab.org/blog/showing-life-opportunities-increasing-opportunity-driven-entrepreneurship-and-stem-careers

#### **NETWORKS AND MEMBERSHIPS**

#### **Innovation for Poverty Action**

[Global, 05/2020 - Current]

https://www.poverty-action.org/people/francisco-flores

#### **International Center for Higher Education Research (INCHER)**

[Kassel, Germany, 05/2019 - Current]

https://www.uni-kassel.de/forschung/en/27/incher/people/flores-francisco

#### **Economics Science Association**

[Global, 05/2018 - Current]

#### **CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS**

### Aspirations, Poverty and Education: Can a role model intervention mitigate the consequences of deprivation? Lessons from Ecuador

[ University of Bologna, 31/08/2022 - 03/09/2022 ]

Flores, F.: Aspirations, Poverty and Education: Can a role model intervention mitigate the consequences of deprivation? Lessons from Ecuador. ESA European Meeting. September 3rd, Bologna (Italy).

https://www.esabologna2022.com/

### Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[ Universidad San Francisco de Quito (USFQ), 04/07/2022 – 07/07/2022 ]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students. Experimental Economics Conference 2022 (USFQ). July 7th, Galapagos (Ecuador). (Co-authors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

https://www.usfg.edu.ec/en/node/3417

### Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[ Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Sloan School of Management (MIT), 13/06/2022 – 16/06/2022 ]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High

School Students. ESA World Meeting. June 15th, Boston (USA). (Co-authors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

https://sites.google.com/wellesley.edu/esaboston2022/welcome

### Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[ University of Chicago, 08/06/2022 - 09/06/2022 ]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High

School Students. Advance in Field Experiments Meeting (AFE). June 9th, Chicago (USA). (Co-authors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

https://economics.uchicago.edu/content/afe2022

### Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[ University of Copenhagen, 29/03/2022 – 29/03/2022 ]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students. Copenhagen Education Network Workshop (CEN). March 29th, Copenhagen (Denmark). (Coauthors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

https://www.cbs.dk/en/research/departments-and-centres/department-of-economics/research/copenhagen-education-network-cen

### Impacts of Personal Initiative and Negotiations Training on Remote-Learning, Time-Use, and Mental Health of Ecuadorian High-School Students during the COVID-19 Quarantine

[Virtual, 10/09/2020 - 12/09/2020]

Flores, F.: Impacts of Personal Initiative and Negotiations Training on Remote-Learning, Time-Use, and Mental Health of Ecuadorian High-School Students during the COVID-19 Quarantine. ESA World Meeting. September 11th, Virtual. (Co-authors: Asanov I., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

https://www.economicscience.org/page/conference/2020-esa-global-online-around-the-clock-meetings

## Showing Life Opportunities: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools

[ Humboldt-University Berlin, 28/06/2018 – 01/07/2018 ]

Flores, F.:Showing Life Opportunities: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools. ESA World Meeting. july 1st, Berlin (Germany). (Co-authors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

https://www.economicscience.org/page/conference/2018-esa-world-meeting-berlin-germany

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Spanish

Other language(s):

**English** German

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

#### My Digital Skills

Programming and Typesetting (Matlab, Python, STATA, R, SQL, Aimms, LATEX) / Microsoft Office / Social Media